Hello everyone, a very warm welcome to all of you.
You are watching You The Real. I am your
own personal advisor Amitraj Sharma. In today's
video, we will learn about Aditya Birla Sun Life's
Guaranteed Milestone Plan.
This plan is a non-lied, non-
participating life insurance plan.
In simple words, you will get a
guaranteed return on the premium you pay. There will be
no risk like equity or stocks here. Along with
this, your
life insurance will remain during the policy term. If something happens to you, the nominee gets the benefit
continuously.
Before I will explain how, let me tell you that the plan has
two different options: single life option
and joint life option.
If you take the joint life option, the age limit is up to 50 years.
In both, you
can cover your spouse under the plan. Please focus the video
on full screen because
now we will learn about the eligibility criteria of Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance Company Limited's Guaranteed
Milestone Plan. The
age limit for taking the plan is from 30 days old to 50 years.  If a
60-year-old person opts for a premium payment
term of 6 years, he will get a policy term of 12 years and 14 years. If he
opts for an 8-year premium payment term, he will get a
policy term of 16 years and 18 years. If he
opts for a 10-year premium payment term, he will get a
policy term of 20 years or 22 years.
If he opts for a 12-year premium payment term,
he will get a policy term of 24 years or 26 years.
So, in this way,
policy terms from 12 to 26 are available. The minimum
maturity age limit is 18 years. If you
opt for a plan for a minor,
he will have to remain under the cover till the age of 18. The minimum
premium limit is ₹1,500,000 per annum. The
minimum maturity limit
is ₹90,000. Talking about the right premium payment mode, you can
pay the premium in yearly, half-yearly, quarterly, monthly installments. The
premium will depend on your age, the
cover you are taking, the policy term, and the
plan option. Let us now know about the
Guaranteed Milestone.  Regarding the benefits of the plan, first of all we will
talk about the death benefit
which is common with both the options.
If you have taken the single life option, then the sum
assured on death will be given
in installments for 10 years. Will the sum assured on death be given every year?
Sum assured on death means that you
will compare your sum assured
till the date of death. Take out 105% of the base premium paid till the date of death.
Then
you will take out 10 times the annual premium.
Whichever is higher among the three will give the sum assured
which will be given to the nominee in installments.
Right, in the single life option, if
you have taken the joint life option and
you are the primary life, if you die, then the
sum assured on death will be given
in annual installments. That is fine for 10 years. Along with that, the
policy will continue with the
secondary life cover. Now,
what will be the secondary life cover?
20% of the life cover you have taken for yourself will be the
life cover of your spouse.
We will consider the same.  If you call it secondary life, the policy will continue, the
premiums will be waived and
your spouse will
also get the maturity benefit in future. However,
if the secondary life, i.e. spouse, dies first, then
you will get a lump sum of 20% for your primary life, i.e. the sum you have taken for yourself. After that, the policy will
continue because you are under the cover and are the
primary life, so you will pay the premium for yourself
and as soon as the policy
term is completed, you will get the
maturity benefit in future. Now, suppose you have
taken the joint life option and if both of you
die, then in such a case, the
policy brochure of the plan tells us that the
benefits will be paid in installments for 10 years only for the
primary life
cover and the amount of secondary life cover will be
given as a lump sum of 20% for the primary life cover. This is how it will happen
and this is what we are
told in the policy document that the policy will
continue, no premium will have to be paid in future
and you will also get the maturity benefit.
But there is
no such example in the policy brochure which can
confirm this. When you go to their website and
read the product details, you do
not find anything like this written there either. So this is a
doubtful case. Well, I have checked, that is why
I am telling you, you can also check it.
Now when it comes to the
maturity benefit of the Guaranteed Milestone Plan, you will get a
Guaranteed Addition along with the Sum Assured Maturity. This Guaranteed
Addition depends on your age, the
policy term you are taking, the plan
option you are choosing, and the premium you are
paying.
Even the rate table of the Guaranteed Addition is not available
in the policy document which can tell. Sum Assured
Maturity means whatever
premium you will pay during the premium payment term.
Suppose Shrima, who is
35 years old, has taken Aditya Birla
Sunlife's Guaranteed Milestone Plan
with single life cover. She has taken a policy term of
20 years and is
paying a premium of Rs. 10000 annually.  So
in such a case what will be the sum assured and maturity? If
we multiply Rs. 50000 by 10 and pay the
premium for 10 years, it will become Rs.
₹ lakh. And what is sum assured? Yes, I understand that
in this plan the annual premium is
15 times. If the annual premium is Rs. 50000, if we
multiply it by 15, then the
sum assured here becomes Rs. 75 lakh. It is mentioned in the policy brochure
that the guaranteed addition will keep
accumulating in the policy every year.
According to our example, Rs. 8288.60 will be received
every year, so we will multiply Rs. 8860 by 20.
If we have taken a policy term of 20 years here, then the
sum assured becomes Rs. 5772. Since
the policy brochure rate table is not available,
we cannot go deeper, so
what will be the maturity benefit?
Sum assured maturity of Rs. 5 lakh and
guaranteed addition of Rs. 5772 i.e. Rs.
772  You will get tax benefits. Whatever premium you
pay, you
can go for rebate of the premium under section 8c.
You can get tax free benefits under section 1010d.
Right, when your annual premium is up
to ₹10 lakh,
for such plans only then the names of the riders available are on
your screen, you
can read them by browsing. You get a free look up period of
30 days. Under this plan,
after taking the policy, if you feel that
no brother, you have taken the wrong policy, then within the first 30
days, you
can cancel the policy and take a refund. The rest of the
details about the benefits have been
given in the ClearTDS video.
Thank you for watching the video till the end. Do like and
share it because only then will the video move forward.